<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Taylor Brazelton</title>
		<link>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Taylor Brazelton</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 10:51:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Replace a Table With View</title>
			<link>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2019/01/replace-table-with-view/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 10:51:38 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2019/01/replace-table-with-view/</guid>
			<description>This weekend while on dev support, an issue came to our attention that customers were still able to see soft deleted data in some parts of the app. Instead of going through all the code and updating each query to return only existing data though, I went directly to the source and replaced the table with a view.
Pros/Cons: Pros: - Easily revertible change. - Apply once, fixes all current queries.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This weekend while on dev support, an issue came to our attention that
customers were still able to see <code>soft deleted</code> data in some parts of the app.
Instead of going through all the code and updating each query to return only
existing data though, I went directly to the source and replaced the table with
a view.</p>

<h4 id="pros-cons">Pros/Cons:</h4>

<p>Pros:
 - Easily revertible change.
 - Apply once, fixes all current queries.
 - Views can still have INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE statements run against them.
 - Good practice from a database design standpoint.</p>

<p>Cons:
 - Someone has to have access to the prod db to do it.
 - Can confuse other developers who are not familiar with views.
 - Depend on the indexes of the table below. You can not put an index on a view.</p>

<h4 id="this-is-how-i-did-it">This is how I did it:</h4>

<p>1) Rename the table.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-SQL" data-lang="SQL"><span class="k">RENAME</span> <span class="k">TABLE</span> <span class="n">chapters</span> <span class="k">TO</span> <span class="n">chapters_all</span><span class="p">;</span></code></pre></div>
<p>2) Create a simple view that filters out deleted data.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-SQL" data-lang="SQL"><span class="k">CREATE</span> <span class="k">VIEW</span> <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">chapters</span><span class="o">`</span> <span class="k">AS</span>
    <span class="k">SELECT</span>
        <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">chapters_all</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="n">id</span><span class="o">`</span> <span class="k">AS</span> <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">id</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">,</span>
        <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">chapters_all</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="n">school</span><span class="o">`</span> <span class="k">AS</span> <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">school</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">,</span>
        <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">chapters_all</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="n">removed</span><span class="o">`</span> <span class="k">AS</span> <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">removed</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">,</span>
        <span class="n">etc</span><span class="p">...</span>
    <span class="k">FROM</span>
        <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">chapters_all</span><span class="o">`</span>
    <span class="k">WHERE</span>
        <span class="p">(</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="n">chapters_all</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="n">removed</span><span class="o">`</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Hope this helps!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Hello World</title>
			<link>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2019/01/hello-world/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:49:57 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2019/01/hello-world/</guid>
			<description>Hello World.
This year I am moving my blog from Pelican to Hugo.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World.</p>

<p>This year I am moving my blog from Pelican to Hugo.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Django Migrations Downgrade in Docker Swarm</title>
			<link>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2018/docker-django-migration-downgrade/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 23:49:57 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2018/docker-django-migration-downgrade/</guid>
			<description>Edge cases are a big problem in software engineering, one that I recently ran into while on a beta box was errors being thrown after a downgrade.
First a little background on the application. It is a django application running in a docker container via docker-swarm. Our application upgrade/downgrade process is to reduce the amount of containers running down to 0. Change the tag numbers in our .yml file and then scale them back up.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Edge cases are a big problem in software engineering, one that I recently ran
into while on a beta box was errors being thrown after a downgrade.</p>

<p>First a little background on the application. It is a django application running
in a docker container via docker-swarm. Our application upgrade/downgrade
process is to reduce the amount of containers running down to 0. Change the
tag numbers in our .yml file and then scale them back up. This forces the
containers to download the newly defined version. Note that our downgrade
process is exactly the same we just update the a tag with an older version.</p>

<p>The process described above might sound correct to you, however, because we use migrations
to structure our database the process is flawed. By replaceing the tag and
just moving to older docker containers, the downgrade function inside our
migrations never get ran. Instead the downgraded application has no idea
about the migrations that existed in the newer version that does not in it&rsquo;s
own. Thus resulting in an inconsistant database state with the version of
application deployed.</p>

<p>My current solution to this issue is to run the migration downgrade for each
app in our django project manually inside of the existing application container
. To do this I start out with a diff of the code between the old version and
the new version. I look for any added migrations and run the command below to
have django south run through the downgrade methods until it reaches the
latest migration in the old code. Then I perform the old migration method.</p>

<p>Here is a step by step list of the process.</p>

<p>1) Diff of code.</p>

<p>2) Write down oldest added migration number and app name</p>

<p>3) Exec into the application docker container.</p>

<p>4) Migrate backwards :</p>

<pre><code>./manage.py migrate appname 0000
</code></pre>

<p>5) Exit out of container.</p>

<p>6) Scale the swarm down to 0 nodes.</p>

<p>7) Change tag number.</p>

<p>8) Scale the containers back up.</p>

<p>Do you have any suggestions or any improvements to this process? Comment below
and link me to other articles you&rsquo;ve read about this process. The more we know
together the better our overall solutions can be.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Strategy for Moving Away From Legacy Code</title>
			<link>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2018/moving-away-from-legacy/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 23:49:57 -0500</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://taylorbrazelton.com/posts/2018/moving-away-from-legacy/</guid>
			<description>1) Chunk Your App Into Pieces  Turn everything into a MICROservice.  2) Modernize Access To Data  Implement Data Access via API&amp;rsquo;s or using a similar data store.
 Developers should not care what it looks like on the backend. They should be able to easly access and manipulate the data in a secure way using their favorite languages.
  3) Replace Decaying Code  Slowly replace chunks of your application one piece at a time.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h5 id="1-chunk-your-app-into-pieces">1) Chunk Your App Into Pieces</h5>

<ul>
<li>Turn everything into a MICROservice.</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="2-modernize-access-to-data">2) Modernize Access To Data</h5>

<ul>
<li><p>Implement Data Access via API&rsquo;s or using a similar data store.</p></li>

<li><p>Developers should not care what it looks like on the backend. They should be
able to easly access and manipulate the data in a secure way using their
favorite languages.</p></li>
</ul>

<h5 id="3-replace-decaying-code">3) Replace Decaying Code</h5>

<ul>
<li>Slowly replace chunks of your application one piece at a time.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="benifits">Benifits:</h4>

<ul>
<li><p>Consolidation of Virtual Machines.</p></li>

<li><p>Easier to move services around.</p></li>

<li><p>Scaling services is easy.</p></li>

<li><p>Chatops</p></li>

<li><p>Use Open Source Technology</p></li>

<li><p>Changes Culture as getting stuff done is very rewarding.</p></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
